is-teledata.com 2019-10-23

# Privacy Policy and Legal Statements | FactSet

## Privacy Policy

Last Revised March 2017

### Introduction

Thank you for visiting www.factset.com, the Website of FactSet Research Systems Inc. and its affiliates (“FactSet” or “we”).  FactSet is a provider of integrated financial information and analytical applications to the global investment community. To protect your privacy better, FactSet wants you to know how we collect your information, the types of information we collect, how we use and share your information and what choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

This policy applies to information we collect:

  * on this Website.
  * in email, text, and other electronic messages between you and this Website.
  * when you interact with our advertising and applications on third-party websites and services, if those applications or advertising include links to this policy.

It does not apply to information collected by:

  * us offline or through any other means, including on any other website operated by Company or any third party (including our affiliates and subsidiaries); or
  * any third party (including our affiliates and subsidiaries), including through any application or content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from or on the Website.

### Collection and Use of Personal Information

We collect several types of information from and about users of our Website, including information:

  * by which you may be personally identified, such as name, postal address, email address, telephone number, etc. ("personal information");
  * about your internet connection, the equipment you use to access our Website and usage details (“usage information”).

We collect this information:

  * directly from you when you provide it to us.
  * automatically as you navigate through the site. Information collected automatically may include usage details, IP addresses, and information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies.

If you provide your personal information to us, we may use that information to service your account, send you news, information or promotions related to our products and services.  In some instances, you may receive information or promotions about products or services offered by another company.

When you have provided personal information to us, we may disclose such information to other companies that we have engaged to assist it in providing you goods or services.  This may include, but is not limited to, fulfillment houses, billing services, transaction managers, credit verification services, and other third party service providers.  We also may disclose your personal information to third party service providers that assist us in conducting market research for our own purposes.  We do not sell personal information to third parties for their own use, but may provide certain usage information to advertisers to help provide you with relevant advertising. 

We may also disclose any of your personal information or usage information to law enforcement or other appropriate third parties in connection with criminal investigations, investigation of fraud, infringement of intellectual property rights, or other suspected illegal activities, as may be required by applicable law, or, as we may deem necessary in our sole discretion, in order to protect our legitimate legal and business interests.

We reserve the right to disclose, share and/or otherwise transfer personal information and usage information, in connection with a corporate merger, acquisition, consolidation, the sale of a portion of our business or the sale of substantially all of our assets, or other fundamental corporate change, whatever form it may take. You will be notified via e-mail or prominent notice on our website prior to a change of ownership or control of your personal information or usage information, if your personal information or usage information will be used contrary to this policy.

### Information You Provide to Us

The information we collect on or through our Website may include:

  * information that you provide by filling in forms on our Website. This includes information provided at the time of requesting information or further services. We may also ask you for information when you enter a contest or promotion sponsored by us, and when you report a problem with our Website.
  * records and copies of your correspondence (including email addresses), if you contact us.
  * your responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete for research purposes.
  * your search queries on the Website. 

### Information We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection Technologies

As you navigate through and interact with our Website, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain usage information about your equipment, browsing actions, and patterns, including:

  * details of your visits to our Website, including traffic data, location data, logs, and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on the Website.
  * information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system, browser type, and internet service provider.

### Use of Cookies and Other Electronic Tools

FactSet and the parties with whom we work (e.g., service providers, business partners, advertisers and advertising servers) may place, view, and/or use cookies, Web server logs, Web beacons, or other electronic tools to collect statistical and other usage information about your use of this Website and all other websites which relate to, provide, or market FactSet products and services. Your consent and acceptance of cookies shall suffice as notice and consent to collection and such usage. This usage information may include information about the IP address of your computer, browser type, language, operating system, your mobile device, geo-location data, internet service provider, the state or country from which you accessed this Web site, the Web pages visited, the date and the time of a visit, the websites you visited immediately before and after visiting this Web site, the number of links you click within this Web site, the functions you use on this Web site, the databases you view and the searches you request on this Web site, the data you save on or download from this Website and the number of times you view an advertisement.

The technologies we use for this automatic data collection may include:

  1. Cookies (or browser cookies). A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Website.
  2. Flash Cookies. Certain features of our Website may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from, and on our Website. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies.
  3. Web Beacons. Pages of our Website and our emails may contain small electronic files known as Web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that permit the Company, for example, to count users who have visited those pages and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity).

We may collect personal information automatically, and we may tie this information to personal information about you that we collect from other sources or you provide to us.

### Collection of Information from Children

We do not seek information directly from children. If you are under 13, you should not provide us with any information without the involvement of a parent or guardian.

We comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act and all other applicable laws and regulations concerning children and the Internet.  If the parent or guardian, of a user who is a minor, discovers that the user has submitted his or her personal information without the parent or guardian’s permission or consent, we will take reasonable steps to remove that information from the Website and our servers at the parent or guardian’s request.  To request removal of personal information of a minor, please contact us as set forth below and be sure to include in the message the user name and legal name of the minor.

### Advertisements

FactSet, its designated service providers, or third-party advertisers or their advertising servers may also place or recognize unique cookies on your computer or use other electronic tools in order to help display advertisements that you see on this Website or on other websites. Information about your visits to, and activity on, this Website and other websites, an IP address, the number of times you have viewed an advertisement, and other such usage information is used, alone or in combination with other information, to display on your device screen advertisements that may be of particular interest to you. We may use Web beacons, provided by third party advertising companies, to help manage and optimize our online advertising and product performance. Web beacons enable us to recognize a browser’s cookie when a browser visits this Website, and to learn which banner ads bring users to this Website. The use and collection of your information by these third party service providers, and third party advertisers and their advertising servers is not covered by this Privacy Policy. To “opt out” of advertising cookies placed by the Network Advertising Initiative’s (“NAI”) online behavioral advertising member networks, and thereby limit the tracking of your online activity and the targeted advertising you receive, please click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). To opt out of advertising cookies for Your Online Choices if you are based in the EU, please click [here](http://youronlinechoices.eu/). To opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising, please click [here](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). You may also enable the “Do Not Track” setting in your web browser(s) or clear cookies from your browser after each browsing session. Please note that even if you exercise choice for targeted advertising, you will still receive online advertising.

### Access

FactSet will enable you to access your personal information held by FactSet and you will be able to correct, amend, or delete that information where it is inaccurate, except (1) where the burden or expenses of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to your privacy in the case in question, or (2) where the rights of persons other than you would be violated. If you wish to access your personal information held by FactSet, you may do so by contacting FactSet’s Global Privacy Officer using the contact information provided below.

Notice to California Residents/Your California Privacy Rights and Canadian Residents: California and Canadian residents are entitled to request and obtain certain information regarding our disclosure, if any, of your personal information and to request updates to such information or revocation of consent of use of such information.  To make such a request, please contact FactSet’s Global Privacy Officer using the contact information provided below.            

### Data Security

FactSet takes reasonable precautions to protect personal information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, altercation, and destruction.  Unfortunately, while we work hard to ensure the security of your personal information while it is on our systems, no security measures are perfect and data transmitted over the Internet cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We cannot and do not ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit and you do so at your own risk.

FactSet is a global company. To offer our services, we may need to transfer your information among several countries, including the United States, where we are headquartered. For information collected from residents of EU member states, FactSet complies with the Standard Contractual Clauses as set forth by the EU regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the EU. FactSet intends to comply with future EU laws related to the transfer of data outside of the EU.

For information collected regarding residents of EU member states, FactSet agrees to cooperate with the Data Protection Authorities located in the EU member states in resolving any individual complaints or disputes with regard to this Privacy Policy and the European Commission’s Directive on Data Protection.

### Links to Other Websites

Our Websites may provide links to other websites for your convenience and information. These websites may operate independently from FactSet. Linked websites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. To the extent any linked websites you visit are not owned or controlled by FactSet, we are not responsible for the websites’ content, any use of the websites, or the privacy practices of the websites.

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. Please review it periodically. Changes to this Policy will be effective upon posting to this Website. Your use of the Website following these changes means that you accept the revised policy.

### How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice, FactSet's privacy practices or if you would like us to update information or preferences you provided to us, please write to us at:

Global Privacy Officer  
FactSet Research Systems Inc.  
601 Merritt 7  
Norwalk, CT 06851  
USA

Privacy Policy

## Legal Statement

 The following terms and conditions govern your use of this web site and all content, services and products available on or through the website (taken together, the "Site"). The Site is owned and operated by FactSet Research Systems Inc. and its affiliates (together, “FactSet”) as a service to its clients and investors and may be used for informational purposes only. Access to and use of the Site is subject to your acceptance without modification of all the terms and conditions contained herein, and all other operating rules, policies, and terms on this Site and any applicable written agreements with FactSet (which, in the event of a conflict with this terms and conditions, shall govern). Single copies of material contained on this Site may be downloaded for non-commercial, personal use subject to the provisions below and provided that you also retain all copyright and other proprietary notices contained on the materials. If you do not agree to these terms, do not use the Site or download any materials from it. If you do not agree to the terms, or if you cannot remain in compliance with such terms, you may not access or use the Site.

FactSet may revise these terms at any time by updating this posting. You should visit this page from time to time to review the then-current terms because they are binding on you. Certain provisions of these terms may be superseded by expressly designated legal notices or terms located on particular pages at this Site.

ACCOUNT RESPONSIBILITY: You are responsible for maintaining the security and confidentiality of your account and password, and you are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your account, whether by you or anyone else. You may not create or use an account for anyone other than yourself. You must immediately notify FactSet of any unauthorized uses of your account or any other breaches of security. FactSet will not be liable for any acts or omissions by you, including any damages of any kind incurred as a result of such acts or omissions. FactSet will not be liable for any loss that you or any other third party may incur as a result of someone else’s use of your account or password, either with or without your knowledge. FactSet may hold you liable for any losses incurred by FactSet or any other party due to someone else’s use of your account or password.

INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY INFORMATION: Unless otherwise noted, product names, designs, logos, titles, text, images, audio,  video and other content within this Site are the trademarks, service marks, trade names, copyrights or other property of FactSet ("FactSet's Intellectual Property") or its third party content providers (“Third Party Intellectual Property”). Nothing contained on the Site should be construed as granting, by implication, estoppel, or otherwise, any license or right to use any of FactSet's Intellectual Property or Third Party Intellectual Property displayed on the Site without the written permission of FactSet. All rights in and to the Site and its content are retained by FactSet. To obtain permission, send an e-mail to [marketing@factset.com](mailto:marketing@factset.com). COPYRIGHT NOTICE: Copyright © 2000-2019 FactSet Research Systems Inc. All rights reserved.

You acknowledge and agree that the contents of this Site, including FactSet’s Intellectual Property and Third Party Intellectual Property, are protected by the copyright laws of the United States and other foreign jurisdictions.

No portion may be reproduced in any form, or by any means, without the prior written consent of FactSet. To obtain reproduction consent, send an e-mail to [marketing@factset.com](mailto:marketing@factset.com).

As FactSet asks others to respect its intellectual property rights, it respects the intellectual property rights of others (please see Acceptable Use Policy below). If you believe that material located on the Site violates your copyright, you are encouraged to notify FactSet at [compliance@factset.com](mailto:compliance@factset.com). FactSet will respond to all such notices, including as required or appropriate by removing the infringing material or disabling all links to the infringing material. FactSet will, to the extent it is able, terminate a user’s access to and use of the Site if, under appropriate circumstances, the user is determined to be a repeat infringer of the copyrights or other intellectual property rights of FactSet or others.

DISCLAIMER AND LIMITATION OF LIABILITY: USE OF THIS WEBSITE IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. THE MATERIALS ON THIS SITE ARE PROVIDED "AS IS" AND “AS AVAILABLE” WITHOUT ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY OF ANY KIND INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, NONINFRINGEMENT OF INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE. YOUR SOLE AND EXCLUSIVE REMEDY IN THE CASE OF DISASTISFACTION WITH THIS SITE OR ANY OTHER GRIEVANCE SHALL BE YOUR TERMINATION AND DISCONTINUANCE OF ACCESS TO OR USE OF THE SITE.

IN NO EVENT SHALL FACTSET OR ITS SUPPLIERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER (INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF PROFITS, BUSINESS INTERRUPTION OR LOSS OF INFORMATION) ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THIS SITE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.

FactSet assumes no responsibility, and shall not be liable for, any such damages to or viruses that may infect your computer equipment, software, data or other property on account of your access to, use of, or browsing in the Site or your downloading of any materials, data, text, images, video or audio from the Site or any linked sites. FactSet and its suppliers further do not warrant the accuracy or completeness of the information, text, graphics, links or other items contained within the materials posted, set forth, downloadable or linked to this Site. FactSet may make changes to or discontinue any or all of these materials, or the products described therein, at any time without notice. FactSet makes no commitment to update the information on this Site.

THE ABOVE LIMITATION OR EXCLUSION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU TO THE EXTENT PROHIBITED BY APLICABLE LAW.

USER SUBMISSIONS: Any content, material, information or other communication, including, without limitation, data, questions, comments, feedback, suggestions or the like (collectively, the "Communications"), that you transmit or post to this Site will be considered non-confidential and non-proprietary. If you transmit or post any Communications to this Site, you hereby grant FactSet a world-wide, royalty free, fully paid, perpetual, irrevocable, and fully assignable, transferable and sublicensable right to use, reproduce, modify, adapt, publish, perform, translate, create derivative works from, distribute, display and otherwise exploit such Communications throughout the world in any form, media or technology, whether now known or hereafter devised or developed.  FactSet will have no obligations in connection with any of the Communications, including but not limited to any obligation to retain or provide you with copies of your Communications or to guarantee any confidentiality with respect to your Communications. FactSet cannot prevent the "harvesting" of information from this Site, and you may be contacted by FactSet or unrelated third parties, by e-mail or otherwise, within or outside of this Site. Furthermore, at the sole discretion of FactSet, the Communications, including all data, images, sounds, text and other things embodied therein, may be edited by or on behalf of FactSet, may or may not be posted to this Site and may be used by FactSet for any purpose, including, reproduction, disclosure, distribution, transmission, publication, broadcast and posting. The Communications may be used by FactSet for any and all commercial or non-commercial purposes including, but not limited to, developing, manufacturing and marketing products using such information.

ACCEPTABLE USE POLICY: You are prohibited from:

  * posting or transmitting to this Site any Communications that are unlawful, threatening, libelous, defamatory, obscene or pornographic or that would otherwise violate any law;
  * posting or transmitting any Communications that could constitute or encourage conduct that would be considered harmful, fraudulent, infringing, offensive, illegal or give rise to civil liability;
  * posting or transmitting any Communications that contain any viruses, worms, malware, Trojan horses or other harmful, destructive or contaminating content;
  * posting or transmitting any unsolicited messages, promotions, advertising, or solicitations (like “spam”) or that is machine- or randomly-generated;
  * copying, modifying, publishing, transmitting, distributing, transferring, selling, creating derivatives of, or in any way exploiting, any material accessible through the website not submitted or provided by you, including by use of any robot, spider, scraper, scripting, deep link or other similar automated gathering or extraction tools, program, algorithm or methodology, unless you obtain FactSet’s prior written consent;
  * using the Site to advertise, market, sell or otherwise promote any commercial enterprise that you own, are employed by or are otherwise compensated by, either directly or indirectly;
  * using this Site in any way to violate the security or integrity of any network, computer or communications system, software application, or network or computing device or otherwise attempt to disrupt or tamper with FactSet servers;
  * attempting to gain unauthorized access to any of the Site or other accounts through hacking, password mining or other means; or
  * using or encouraging, promoting, facilitating or instructing others to use the Site in any matter not explicitly permitted under these terms.

FactSet has the right (but not the obligation) to monitor activity on the Site and investigate any violation of this Agreement or misuse of the Site. If you become aware of any violation of this Agreement or misuse of the Site, you must immediately notify us and provide us with assistance, as requested, to stop or remedy such violation. FactSet hereby notifies you that it will cooperate fully with any law enforcement authorities or court order requesting or directing FactSet to disclose the identity of or help identify or locate anyone posting any such information or materials. FactSet further has the right (but not the obligation) to refuse or remove any Communications from this Site or terminate or deny access to and use of the Site for any reason. FactSet is under no obligation to enforce these terms on your behalf against another user. FactSet reserves the right to take appropriate action in its sole discretion.

You hereby represent and warrant that (a) your use of the Site will not infringe the proprietary rights of any third party; (b) your use of the Site will be in strict accordance with these and any other applicable terms and with all applicable laws and regulations; (c) that any Communication you post or transmit to the Site is accurate.

USER RESPONSIBILITY **:** FactSet has not reviewed, and cannot review, all of the Communications and material posted to the Site, and therefore cannot be responsible for its content, use or effects. By operating the Site, FactSet does not represent or imply that it endorses the material there posted, or that it believes such material to be accurate, useful, lawful or non-harmful. Neither FactSet nor any of this third party suppliers guarantees, endorses, or is otherwise responsible or liable for the accuracy, completeness, timeliness, reliability, availability, or usefulness of any Communications and material accessible through the Site. The information provided on this Site by FactSet speaks only as of the respective dates on which the information was first created. This information can become out-of-date. FactSet makes no commitment, and disclaims any duty, to update any of this information, except as expressly stated on this Site. You use this Site at your own risk and are responsible for taking precautions as necessary to protect yourself and your computer systems.

USE OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION: Information submitted to FactSet on this Site is governed according to FactSet's Online Privacy Policy.

LINKS TO OTHER MATERIALS: The linked sites are not under the control of FactSet, and FactSet is not responsible for the content, including, without limitation, the truthfulness or accuracy of any statement or other content, of any linked site or any link contained in a linked site. FactSet reserves the right to terminate any link or linking program at any time. FactSet has not reviewed all the information contained in the linked sites and does not endorse the companies, products or sites to which it links and reserves the right to note as such throughout the Site. If you decide to access any of the third-party sites linked to our Site, you do this entirely at your own risk.

INDEMNIFICATION: You agree to indemnify, defend and hold harmless FactSet, its contractors, and its third-party suppliers, and their respective directors, officers, employees and agents from and against any and all claims, costs, liabilities and expenses (including attorneys’ fees) arising out of your use of the Site, including but not limited to your violation of these terms. FactSet reserves the right, at your expense, to control the defense of these claims. You agree not to settle any claims without FactSet’s written consent. You agree to notify FactSet immediately in writing of any such claims.

TERMINATION: FactSet may terminate your access to all or any part of the Site at any time, with or without cause, with or without notice, effectively immediately. If you wish to terminate these terms, or your user account (if you have one), you may simply discontinue using the Site. All provisions of these terms which by their nature should survive termination shall survive, including, without limitation, intellectual property ownership provisions, warranty disclaimers, indemnity and limitations of liability.  

APPLICABLE LAWS: This site is controlled by FactSet from its offices located in the State of Connecticut within the United States of America. FactSet does not make any representation that materials at this Site are appropriate or available for use outside the United States, and access to them from territories where the content of this Site is illegal is prohibited. While this Site may be viewed internationally and may contain references to products and services not available in all countries, such references do not imply that FactSet intends to make such products or services available in such countries. You may neither use, export or re-export the materials at this Site, nor may you use any copy or adaptation of such materials, in each case, in violation of any applicable laws or regulations, including, without limitation, United States export laws and regulations. Except to the extent applicable law provides otherwise, these terms, any access to or use of the Site, will be governed by the laws of the State of Connecticut within the United States of America, excluding its conflict of law provisions, and the proper venue for any disputes arising out of or relating to any of the same will be the state and federal course located in Connecticut.

GENERAL: If any part of these terms is held invalid or unenforceable, that part will be construed to reflect the parties’ original intent, and the remaining portions will remain in full force and effect. A waiver by either party of any term or condition of these terms or any breach thereof, in any one instance, will not waive such term or condition or any subsequent breach thereof. You may not assign or otherwise transfer your rights under this Agreement to any party, including by operation of law. FactSet may assign or otherwise transfer its rights under this Agreement without condition. This Agreement will be binding upon and will inure the benefit of the parties, their successors and permitted assigns.

These terms were last updated October 16, 2018.

Legal Statement

## GDPR Data Protection Notice

Last Revised May 17, 2018

### 1\. Introduction

Thank you for visiting www.factset.com, the Website of FactSet Research Systems Inc. and its affiliates (“FactSet” or “we”).  FactSet is a provider of integrated financial information and analytical applications to the global investment community. To protect your privacy better, FactSet wants our customers, suppliers and other relevant parties to know how we collect personal data, the types of personal data we collect, and how we use and share your personal data when we act as the controller of that personal data that is subject to the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Hence this notice only applies to personal data which is subject to GDPR and which we collect:

  * on this Website;
  * on client and supplier facing applications and tools (e.g. Workstations, Starboard and Gateway, Object Reference, Endpoint Reference, Confluence, Jira);
  * in email, text, and other electronic messages between you and our employees; when you interact with our advertising and applications on third-party websites and services, if those applications or advertising include links to this notice;
  * from customers and suppliers subject to contractual relationships;  
from public and third party sources for the purposes of providing and/or administrating our content services;

It does not apply to any other personal data, and notably personal data collected by:

  * any third party regardless whether collected through any application; or
  * any content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from or on the Website.

### 2\. Summary

We collect and process personal data mainly from our customers and suppliers while doing business with them and we collect and receive personal data on this Website and through social networks (see more information under section 3). The personal data we process is mainly business contact information from our clients and suppliers and also information you and our customers provide when using our products or accessing our websites or other applications (see more information under sections 4 and 5). We also collect and collate information (including some personal data) from third party suppliers and public sources to make available to our customers as part of the services we offer to them (see more information under section 6).  We mainly process the personal information in order to provide our services and to fulfill our contractual obligations and to improve our products and offerings (see more information under sections 7 and 8). We do not sell such personal data to third parties for their own use but we might share it with third parties when there is a legal requirement to do so or where we need a third party to fulfill our services (see more information under section 9). We transfer personal data within our group based on an Intragroup-Data-Transfer-Agreement which subject to the GDPR (see more information under section 10). You can learn more about where and how we use cookies related to our Website and services by reading section 11. This notice informs you also about our retention policy (section 12). You have rights in respect of your personal data. To learn more about those rights, please read section 14. You will also find our contact information at the end of this notice under section 17.

### 3\. Personal Data that we collect

We collect several types of information and personal data:

  * that relates to an identified or identifiable individual, such as name, postal address, email address, telephone number, IP or MAC address etc. and related information, such as the contents of an email ("personal data"); 
    * about your internet connection, the equipment you use to access our Website and usage details (e.g. statistics) regarding our products (“usage information”).

We collect this information and personal data:

  * directly from you and/your employees when you or they provide it to us;
  * automatically as you and/or your employees navigate through the site and/or use our products. Information and personal data collected automatically may include usage information, IP addresses, and information and personal data collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies; 
    * from public and third party sources.

### 4\. Personal Data You Provide to Us

The personal data we collect may include:

  * personal data that you provide by conducting business with us, by filling in forms on our Website, or at a trade show, or anywhere else we conduct business, by subscribing to newsletters or other communications, or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise using our contact details. This includes personal data provided at the time of requesting information or services, soliciting business or performing a service. We may also ask you for personal data when you enter a contract with us, or a contest or promotion sponsored by us, and when you report a problem;
  * records and copies of your correspondence (including email addresses);
  * your responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete for research purposes;
  * your search queries on the Website;
  * during the contractual relationship for execution of the supplier or customer contract;
  * by using our incident management and project management tools and applications;
  * by communicating with our customer care teams for error resolving issues, training and support; 
    * Your usage of our products and relating tools and applications.

Typically, the personal data you give us may include name, business affiliation, business address, telephone number, and email address, and any personal details required to conduct business with you or to resolve any enquiries or complaints.

We will indicate to you when personal data is required to enter into a contract with you (such as in anticipation of a services agreement) or to perform a contract with you (such as to provide services at your request), and failure to provide any personal data may result in our inability to provide requested services or products.

### 5\. Personal Data We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection Technologies

If you navigate through and interact with our Website and some of our products, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain usage information about your equipment, browsing actions, and patterns. Automatic data collection is carried out through the use of cookies and related technologies.  For more information, please see section (11).

### 6\. Personal Data We Collect From Public Sources and Third Parties

In order to provide our content services to our customers, we rely on content provided by third party suppliers, as well as content that is available to the public. Some of that content includes general information about names of directors, registered board members, managers, fund managers and other official persons of companies published on public accessible websites, letterheads, prospects, annual financial statements, invitations to shareholder meetings etc.

### 7\. Lawful Grounds for Processing

All processing and use of your personal data is justified by a "lawful ground" for processing. In the majority of cases, processing will be justified on the lawful ground that:

  * the processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps to enter into a contract at your request, such as to negotiate a contract with us, to fill an order, or to provide product information that you have requested;
  * the processing is necessary for us to comply with a relevant legal obligation, such as keeping accounting records;
  * the processing is in our legitimate interests, which are not overridden by the interests and rights of the relevant individual whose personal data is collected; and
  * you have consented to the processing.

Where we rely on our legitimate interests to process personal data, those interests are:

  * to use supplier, customer and website user data to conduct and develop our business activities and improve our services in order to grow our business and profitability, while limiting the use of their personal data to purposes that support the conduct and the development of our business and the improvement of our services;

  * to use third party supplier and publicly available content (which in some instances includes personal data) in order to provide our content services to customers for their business purposes, which may include, but not be limited to taking investment decisions or compliance with applicable laws and regulations such as insider trading regulations and anti-bribery legislation, but which are for our customers to determine and explain in their privacy notices).

### 8\. Why We Collect Personal Data

The following is an overview of our purposes for using your personal data. Additional details on how we process your personal data may be provided to you in a separate notice or contract.

We use the personal data we collect to:

  * provide customer services, including products and services; to take, verify, process, and deliver orders and returns; to process payments, technical support, or other similar purposes; and to establish and maintain customer accounts;
  * to provide training and after-sales-support on our products and answer to and perform change requests;
  * to organize and perform incident management processes;
  * to implement projects by working together with customers and their users as part of the project team;
  * communicate with customers and suppliers, including responding to requests for assistance and to update them about the status of their orders by postal mail, email, telephone, and/or text message;
  * investigate, prevent or take action regarding unauthorized use of our services, illegal activities, suspected fraud or situations involving potential threats;
  * to provide you with underlying tools and applications helping to implement projects and solving incidents;
  * to discuss, carry out and implement change request and further developments of our products;
  * to provide our content services to our customers and to report and administer customers’ users’ usage of third party information products (e.g. real-time data from stock exchanges etc.);
  * administer and manage performance of purchase or sales agreements with our suppliers and customers;
  * to enhance the experience for our users, we use notes relating to support provided to specific employees, advisors or agents of customers in relation to our products and services for their future use of our services;
  * service your account;
  * market and promote our products including through email or equivalent electronic means, to send news and newsletters, special offers and promotions, or to otherwise contact customers about products, services or information;
  * process, evaluate and complete certain transactions involving the website, and more generally transactions involving FactSet's products and services;
  * operate, evaluate, maintain, improve and develop the Website (including by monitoring and analysing trends, tracking user behavior, access to, and use of the website for advertising and marketing);
  * engage with you about events, promotions, the Website and FactSet's products and services;
  * provide you with documentation or communications which you have requested or which is part of a product;
  * correspond with users to resolve their queries or complaints;
  * send you marketing communications, where it is lawful for us to do so;
  * protect the security of the Website, FactSet confidential and proprietary information (which may include personal data), and FactSet employees;
  * manage, protect against and investigate fraud, risk exposure, claims and other liabilities, including but not limited to violation of our contract terms or laws or regulations; 
    * share your personal data with third parties in connection with potential or actual sale of our company or any of our assets, or those of any affiliated company, in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

FactSet will not sell or rent your personal data you provided to us to third parties.

### 9\. Sharing Your Personal Data

When you have provided personal data to us, we may disclose such personal data to other companies that we have engaged to assist us in providing you goods or services.  This may include, but is not limited to, fulfillment houses, billing services, transaction managers, credit verification services, and other third-party service providers.  We also may disclose your personal data to third party service providers that assist us in conducting market research for our own purposes.  We do not sell personal data to third parties for their own use, but may provide certain usage information to advertisers to help provide you with relevant advertising. 

We may also disclose any of your personal data or usage information to law enforcement or other appropriate third parties in connection with criminal investigations, investigation of fraud, infringement of intellectual property rights, or other suspected illegal activities, as may be required by applicable law, or, as we may deem necessary in our sole discretion, in order to protect our legitimate legal and business interests.

We reserve the right to disclose, share and/or otherwise transfer personal data and usage information in connection with a proposed or actual corporate merger, acquisition, consolidation, the sale of a portion of our business or the sale of substantially all of our assets, or other fundamental corporate change, whatever form it may take. You will be notified via a prominent notice on our website prior to a change of ownership or control of your personal data or usage information.

### 10\. Transferring Personal Data

FactSet is a global organization headquartered in the United States, and we may need to transfer your personal data to third party suppliers and to our affiliates for the purposes described above.  If your personal data is subject to the GDPR and is transferred outside the EU to other FactSet affiliates or to third party service providers, we will take steps to ensure that your personal data receives the same level of protection as if it remained within the EU, including by entering into data transfer agreements using the European Commission approved Standard Contractual Clauses, or by relying on certification schemes such as the EU – US Privacy Shield.  For transfers of personal data among FactSet affiliates we have put in place European Commission-approved Standard Contractual Clauses and have entered into an Intragroup data transfer agreement. You have a right to obtain details of the mechanism under which your personal data is transferred outside of the EU, although please note that we may need to redact copies of transfer agreements for reasons of commercial confidentiality, provided that you can retain access to the relevant safeguards.

FactSet reserves the right to share any information that you provide which is not deemed personal data or is not otherwise subject to contractual restrictions.

### 11\. Use of Cookies and Other Electronic Tools

Our Website uses technologies that enhance user friendliness and engagement, to keep the Website operating as smoothly as possible and to provide web services and functionalities for each visitor. Examples of these technologies are cookies, pixel tags, local storage and scripts:

  * Cookies (or browser cookies). A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Website.
  * Flash Cookies. Certain features of our Website may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information (including personal data) about your preferences and navigation to, from, and on our Website. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies. 
    * Web Beacons. Pages of our Website and our emails may contain small electronic files known as Web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that permit the Company, for example, to count users who have visited those pages and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity).

We may collect personal data automatically, and we may tie this personal data to personal data about you that we collect from other sources or you provide to us.

In this Policy, we refer to cookies, flash cookies and web beacons as "cookies".

Cookies are used for a variety of purposes. For example, they calculate web statistics, provide online adversiting and they improve visitor's experience on our Website. As your privacy is important to us, we would like to inform you about which cookies are used on our Website, as well as why we use them. We use the following cookies on our Website:

  * Functional cookies: these cookies are essential in order to ensure that our Website operates properly. They are used to save preferences, detect misuse of our Website and services and to distribute the load on our servers, which keeps our Website available. Certain services you may request cannot be provided without these cookies.
  * Web statistics cookies: these cookies are used to determine which parts of our Website interest our visitors. This enables us to make the structure, navigation, and content of our Website as user friendly as possible.  We and the parties with whom we work (e.g., service providers, business partners, advertisers and advertising servers) may place, view, and/or use cookies, Web server logs, Web beacons, or other electronic tools to collect statistical and other usage information about your use of this Website and all other websites which relate to, provide, or market FactSet products and services. This usage information may include information about the IP address of your computer, browser type, language, operating system, your mobile device, geo-location data, internet service provider, the state or country from which you accessed this Web site, the Web pages visited, the date and the time of a visit, the websites you visited immediately before and after visiting this Web site, the number of links you click within this Web site, the functions you use on this Web site, the databases you view and the searches you request on this Web site, the data you save on or download from this Website and the number of times you view an advertisement. Software from third parties (Google Analytics ) may be used for these purposes. Information generated by the use of Google Analytics may be transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the US.
  * Social media cookies: our Website may integrate certain third-party plug-ins (such as a Facebook "like" button).  Even if you do not click on these plug-ins, they may collect information about you, such as your IP address and the pages that you view. These plugins are governed by the privacy policy of the third party providing them.
  * Advertising cookies: our Website may also enable third-party tracking mechanisms to collect data over time and across unaffiliated websites for use in interest-based advertising. For example, third parties may use the fact that you visited the Website to send you online ads for FactSet products on third party websites.  In addition, our third-party advertising partners might use information about you to send you targeted advertisements based on your online behavior in general. Information (including personal data) about your visits to, and activity on, this Website and other websites, an IP address, the number of times you have viewed an advertisement, and other such usage information is used, alone or in combination with other information and personal data, to display on your device screen advertisements that may be of particular interest to you. We may use Web beacons, provided by third party advertising companies, to help manage and optimize our online advertising and product performance. Web beacons enable us to recognize a browser’s cookie when a browser visits this Website, and to learn which banner ads bring users to this Website. The use and collection of your information and personal data by these third party service providers, and third party advertisers and their advertising servers is not covered by this Privacy Notice. 

To opt out of advertising cookies for Your Online Choices if you are based in the EU, please click [here](http://youronlinechoices.eu/). To opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising, please click [here](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). You may also enable the “Do Not Track” setting in your web browser(s) or clear cookies from your browser after each browsing session. Please note that even if you exercise choice for targeted advertising, you will still receive online advertising.

  * Matching or connecting cookies: We or our third-party service providers also may use collected information to establish connections among related web browsers and devices (such as smartphones, tablets, computers, and TVs) for targeted advertising, analytics, attribution, and reporting purposes. These third parties may match your browsers or devices if you log into the same online service on multiple devices or if your devices share similar attributes that support an inference that they are used by the same person or household. This means that information about your activity on Website or apps on your current browser or device may be combined with information collected from your other browsers or devices.
  * Other cookies: this category includes cookies that do not fit into one of the above cookie categories. One example of this is the bundling of several of the cookies via Google Tag Manager.

How to manage cookies

If you do not want our Website to store cookies on your device, you can change your browser settings so that you receive a warning before certain cookies are stored. You can also adjust your settings so that your browser refuses most of our cookies or only certain cookies from third parties. You can also withdraw your consent to cookies by deleting the cookies that have already been stored.

Please be aware that if you do not want to accept any cookies, we cannot guarantee that our Website will function properly. It may be that several functions will be unavailable to you or that you will even be unable to view certain parts of the Website.

Please note that you will have to change your settings for each browser and device you use. Moreover, such methods will not work with respect to certain non-cookie online tracking technologies.

The procedures for changing your settings and cookies differ from browser to browser. If necessary, use the help function on your browser or click on one of the links below to go directly to the user manual for your browser.

There are also software products available that can manage cookies for you. You can also use [www.ghostery.com](http://www.ghostery.com/) to accept or refuse each cookie used on our Website.

To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage or delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### 12\. Retention of Your Personal Data

We keep personal data only for as long as required to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected.  In general, we retain personal data for a period of time corresponding to a statute of limitation, for example to maintain an accurate record of customer and supplier dealings. However, in some circumstances we may retain personal data for other periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax or accounting requirements, or if required to do so by a legal process, legal authority, or other governmental entity having authority to make the request, for so long as required in accordance with our document retention policy.

### 13\. Your Rights

We will take steps in accordance with applicable legislation to keep personal data accurate, complete and up-to-date. You are entitled to have any inadequate, incomplete or incorrect personal data corrected (that is, rectified). You also have the right to request access to your personal data as well as to obtain additional personal data about the processing. In the event the lawful ground (see Lawful Grounds for Processing above) for processing your personal data is your consent, you have the right to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing before withdrawal. Further, you are entitled to object to the processing of your personal data or to have your personal data erased, under certain circumstances.

As from 25 May 2018, the following rights also apply solely to processing of personal data which is subject to the GDPR.  Each right may only apply in certain circumstances, and subject to exemptions under either EU or Member State law:

  * Data portability.
  * Right to erasure.
  * Right to restriction of processing.
  * Right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority.
  * Right to object to processing (including profiling) based on legitimate interest lawful grounds.
  * Right to object to direct marketing  (including profiling).

Please contact us as indicated in How To Contact Us or using the email-address: [DataPrivacy@Factset.com](mailto:DataPrivacy@Factset.com) if you wish to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any enquiries or complaints regarding the processing of your personal data.

### 14\. Data Security

FactSet takes reasonable precautions to protect personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, altercation, and destruction.  Unfortunately, while we work hard to ensure the security of your personal data while it is on our systems, no security measures are perfect and data transmitted over the Internet cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We cannot and do not ensure or warrant the security of any personal data you transmit and you do so at your own risk.

### 15\. Links to Other Websites

Our Websites may provide links to other websites for your convenience and information. These websites may operate independently from FactSet. Linked websites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. To the extent any linked websites you visit are not owned or controlled by FactSet, we are not responsible for the websites’ content, any use of the websites, or the privacy practices of the websites.

### 16\. Changes to Our Privacy Notice

This Privacy Notice may be amended from time to time. Please review it periodically. Changes to this Notice will be announced on this Website in advance.

### 17\. How to Contact Us

To exercise any of your rights described at Your Rights or to contact us please use the email-address: [DataPrivacy@factset.com](mailto:DataPrivacy@factset.com) or if you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice, FactSet's privacy practices, or if you would like us to update personal data or preferences you provided to us, please write to us at:

In the US:   
Global Privacy Officer  
FactSet Research Systems Inc.  
601 Merritt 7  
Norwalk, CT 06851  
USA

In Europe:  
FactSet UK Limited  
Broadgate Quarter  
1 Snowden Street  
London EC2A 2DQ, UK

For activities related to Germany and the Philippines, we have a data protection officer in each of these countries:

Germany DPO:  
KINAST Rechtsanwaltsgesellschaft mbH  
Herr Rechtsanwalt Dr. Karsten Kinast, LLM.  
Hohenzollernring 54  
D-50672 Köln  
Telephone: +49 221 - 222 183 0  
E-mail: [mail@kinast.eu  
](mailto:mail@kinast.eu)Web: [www.kinast.eu](http://www.kinast.eu/)

The Philippines DPO:  
Allan Ong     
FactSet Philippines,Inc.  
8/F Commerce and Industry Plaza,McKinley  
Town Center Taguig City Metro  
Manila 1364  
Telephone: +632-908-2600  
E-mail: [DataPrivacy@FactSet.com](mailto:DataPrivacy@FactSet.com)

GDPR Data Protection Notice

## FactSet's UK Modern Slavery Act Statement 2018

This statement is made pursuant to section 54(1) of the United Kingdom Modern Slavery Act of 2015 and constitutes FactSet’s group slavery and human trafficking statement for the financial year ending 31 August 2018.

### Introduction from Phil Snow, Chief Executive Officer

As a major software and solutions provider globally, we recognise that our company must act responsibly and thus are committed to improving our practices to combat slavery and human trafficking. Employees are expected to report concerns, using the appropriate reporting channels, and management are expected to act upon them. We are proud of the corporate social responsibility work we carry out in our local communities. As we expand into new markets, we ensure that corporate social responsibility is a key part of our business strategic development plans.

### Organisation's Structure and Business

We are a major supplier of online-integrated financial and economic information to the investment management and banking industries. FactSet Research Systems Inc. is the parent company of all our global subsidiaries, including our businesses in the United Kingdom (“FactSet”). FactSet has 9,500 employees worldwide in 64 office locations in 24 countries.

### Our Supply Chains

FactSet is not in an industry with a high risk of modern slavery or human trafficking. Our supply chains include suppliers based throughout the world that provide a range of services and products, from third party data providers to IT infrastructure and local food service. FactSet is committed to high professional standards and ethics and we expect the same from all our suppliers. All suppliers are expected to comply with all local and national laws and regulations.

### Our Values and Policies

Part of our values and culture is that we are an inclusive community, working together as a team and staying connected to our clients and each other. We are committed to ensuring that there is no modern slavery or human trafficking in our supply chains or in any part of our business. We are currently exploring implementing supplier policies to support our commitment to act ethically and with integrity in all our business relationships. We seek to implement and enforce effective systems and controls to ensure slavery and human trafficking is not taking place anywhere in our supply chains.

### Employees

Giving back to our communities is an integral part of our culture. FactSet employees have always driven our corporate social responsibility efforts, embracing volunteerism, giving, and sustainability initiatives. We have established a globally consistent programme grounded in four Pillars of Service – ‘Inspiring Tomorrow’s Engineers’, ‘Elevate to Educate’, ‘Alleviating Food Insecurity’ and ‘Protecting our Environment’. We developed dozens of new community partnerships and established CSR Committees led by 150 employees across 26 offices who are engaging our colleagues in service projects within our pillars that are both highly impactful for our communities and engage our employees in meaningful volunteer opportunities.

Our employees served more than 13,000 volunteer hours in FY17. Increased number of volunteer events by 77% from FY17. Examples of the volunteer work include: FactSet’s Global Hunger Awareness Week 2018 which through our financial support and volunteerism, provided over 145,600 meals for people in need, helping to meet basic human needs; launching our first global Season of Service in FY18, engaging more than 2,000 employees who served more than 6,200 volunteer hours across our four pillars; mentoring young future science and technology leaders; introducing young people to coding and computer science; supporting financial literacy programmes for school children and adults; providing books and desks to rural school children in India; supporting food banks and food rescue programmes in many of our offices globally; and working with conservation organisations to contribute to biodiversity studies and clean up green spaces in the communities in which we operate.

Our Corporate Social Responsibility Report is available on our public website and details how we manage our global business through our fair and transparent governance processes and equip our staff to uphold the highest standards of ethics.

Our Code of Conduct and Ethics guides our employees and is available on our public website and our intranet site. If employees have any concerns about any wrongdoing or breaches of law, these can be raised through appropriate channels. In situations where employees prefer to place an anonymous or confidential report, they are encouraged to use FactSet’s Ethics Action Line which is accessible on our intranet site.

### Next Steps

We will continue to review the effectiveness of the steps we have taken to ensure that there is no slavery or human trafficking in our supply chains, and assess emergent risks, if any arise, regarding slavery and human trafficking in our supply chains. We will also explore developing a supplier code of conduct for suppliers, setting out our standards and commitment to anti-slavery and human trafficking laws, as well other standards.

This statement was approved by the board of FactSet Research Systems Inc., FactSet Europe Limited and FactSet UK Limited.

Phil Snow

Chief Executive Officer

Date: March 27, 2019

UK Modern Slavery Act

## UK Tax Strategy

**Financial year ending August 31, 2018**

FactSet Research Systems Inc. (the “Company” or “FactSet”) is a multinational company headquartered in Norwalk, Connecticut, United States with operations across 23 countries. FactSet was founded in 1978 and provides integrated financial information and analytical applications for the global investment community.

### **Introduction to FactSet’s UK Tax Strategy**

FactSet has substantial local operations and presence in the UK. FactSet is committed to conduct its tax affairs in accordance with the following objectives:

  * Act as a responsible global corporate tax citizen in compliance with applicable tax law, regulations and reporting disclosure requirements;
  * Maintain an open relationship with tax authorities based on collaboration and integrity;
  * Apply diligence and care in the management of processes and procedures by which all tax related activities are undertaken;
  * Encourage ethical and transparent business practices;
  * Use available incentives and reliefs while ensuring that these reliefs are not used for purposes which are knowingly contradictory to the intent of the legislation.

### **Risk Management and Governance**

FactSet believes that it is important to pay the correct amount of tax at the right time, under all relevant laws and regulations. We are committed to provide transparent and accessible information to tax administrators in order to facilitate an understanding of our tax strategy and the underlying business models. We operate an effective tax control framework to identify key tax risks and to manage those risks through appropriately designed and operated controls, polices and processes.

### Tax Strategy and Strategic Objectives

Generally, FactSet’s tax strategy and strategic objectives are intended to establish a clear and unequivocal approach to all aspects of tax reporting and compliance.

Our strategy is focused on ensuring that taxes (and tax risks) are managed to provide outcomes consistent with commercial reality and are within the parameters of our strategic objectives. The strategy also requires that all tax obligations are complied with in the UK and all other relevant jurisdictions.

With the tax landscape constantly changing, FactSet’s tax affairs and tax risk management procedures are regularly reviewed to ensure that processes and measures are up-to-date so that we are able to identify, assess, manage and mitigate tax risk as well as remain aligned with FactSet’s business strategy and governance framework.

### **Level of Acceptable Tax Risk**

We aim for certainty on the tax positions we adopt, so diligent professional care and judgment is employed to assess tax risks arising from our commercial operations. We seek to reduce the level of tax risk arising from operations as far as is practically reasonable through an ongoing commitment to improving internal control effectiveness and by ensuring that all tax or tax-related processes are allocated to appropriately qualified owners.

FactSet’s level of acceptable risk is low, and we structure our affairs based on sound commercial principles and in accordance with company policy and relevant tax legislation. FactSet will consider different tax outcomes when considering how to undertake commercially motivated transactions, but does not participate in aggressive tax planning for the purposes of tax avoidance or engage in tax schemes that go against the intention of the legislative authority.

### **Approach towards Dealings with HM Revenue & Customs (“HMRC”)**

It is FactSet’s general policy to be transparent and proactive in all interactions with HMRC.

We have an open, honest and positive working relationship with HMRC. We are committed to prompt disclosure and transparency in all tax matters with HMRC. We recognize that there will be areas of differing legal interpretations between ourselves and HMRC and where this occurs we will engage in proactive discussion to bring matters to as rapid a conclusion as possible.

UK Tax Strategy

## Accommodation Statement 

FactSet endeavors to make [https://www.factset.com/careers](https://www.factset.com/careers?hsLang=en-us) accessible to any and all users. If you would like to contact us regarding the accessibility of our website or need assistance completing the application process, please contact Kristen Panichella, Global Director, Talent Acquisition at [Recruiting2@factset.com](mailto:Recruiting2@factset.com). This contact information is for accommodation requests only and cannot be used to inquire about the status of applications. 

FactSet is an equal opportunity employer. Qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, national origin, disability or protected veteran status. For our EEO Policy Statement, please click here. If you’d like more information on your EEO rights under the law, please click here. For the EEO Commission, please [click here](https://www.eeoc.gov/employers/smallbusiness/checklists/employee_rights.cfm).

Accommodation Statement 

## EU/EEA Job Candidate Privacy Notice

FactSet (the " **Company**  profile ") (" **we** ", " **our** " or " **us** ") collects and processes information that identifies you (" **Personal Data** ") in connection with your application for a job with the Company. This Job Candidate Privacy Notice (" **Notice** ") provides important information about our use of your Personal Data.

The FactSet entity with whom you are applying for a role is the main controller of your Personal Data, other companies within the FactSet group may also need to process your Personal Data in order to make decisions about the hiring process.

This Notice does not constitute an offer of employment, does not form part of any contract and does not confer any contractual right on you, or place any contractual obligation on us.

**1\. Summary**

_We collect and use personal details which you provide as part of the recruitment process, and may also obtain details from third parties (such as referees (references) or background checks)._

_We may retain your application for a limited period for future opportunities. Your data may be stored in systems based around the world, and may be processed by third party service providers acting on our behalf._

_You have certain rights in respect of your personal data, which you can exercise using the contact information set out below._

**2\. Personal Data**

We may collect various types of Personal Data about you for the purposes described in this Notice, including:

  * _Data about you:  _such as your forename, surname, gender, nationality, date of birth, home contact details (e.g. address, telephone number, e-mail), national ID number, immigration and eligibility to work data;
  * _Data about your employment history and qualifications:  _qualifications, references, CV and application form, background checks and verification of information from LinkedIn or similar social media profile;
  * D _ata about your application:_  such as interview notes or assessment results; and
  * _Legal and criminal records data:_  legal records data is processed only in compliance with the applicable laws and in specific circumstances (e.g., background checks for senior roles or roles handling sensitive information).

**3\. Sources of Personal Data**

You may give us the Personal Data described above during the recruitment process, whether through the application forms on our online job portal, on the telephone or at interviews. We partner with certain third party jobsites, such as LinkedIn or JobCentre Plus, and may receive your Personal Data via these organisations.

We may also receive Personal Data about you from other third parties; for example, recruiters; references from a previous employer; business partners; background check providers; as well as from publicly available sources such as social media.

**4\. Why we process your Personal Data   **

The Personal Data requested from you during the recruitment process is required by us in order to:

  * assess your application for employment with the Company;
  * evaluate and grade applicants;
  * set-up and conduct interviews and tests;
  * carry out right to work checks, background checks, verify your application, contact referees (references) and, where permitted by law, carry out criminal record checks;
  * make employment offers, or communicate the rejection of applications; and
  * retain your application for a limited period of time, to consider you for future, similar opportunities.

If you do not provide some or all of this Personal Data it may affect our ability to process your application, and in some cases, it may mean that we are unable to continue with your application as the Company will not have the Personal Data we believe to be necessary for the effective and efficient management of the recruitment process.

We process your Personal Data on one of the following legal bases:

  * the processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Company is subject (such as verifying eligibility for employment or complying with obligations regarding non-discrimination);
  * the processing is necessary in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into an employment contract with you (such as verifying qualifications and work history);
  * the processing is based on consent (only used in limited circumstances, such as your option to opt-in to a longer period of retention for unsuccessful applications); or
  * the processing is necessary for the legitimate interests pursued by the Company in hiring qualified and appropriate staff members, except where such interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms which require protection of personal data.

The processing of legal or criminal records data will be undertaken where permitted by applicable laws, national collecting bargaining agreements and binding resolutions of the relevant Supervisory Authority for data protection.

**5.  Disclosure and transfer of Personal Data**

For the purposes listed under section 4 above, we may share your Personal Data with other members of the FactSet group (including in countries outside EU/EEA, such as the United States of America, India and the Philippines). For example, some of our recruitment and applicant testing applications are hosted in the U.S., and some hiring decisions involve input or review from other FactSet group companies. FactSet has adopted an Intra-Group Data Transfer Agreement to ensure your Personal Data receives an adequate level of protection wherever it is processed within the FactSet group.

Your Personal Data may also be accessed by third parties who provide us with services, such as recruiters, and companies hosting, supporting and maintaining the IT systems supporting our recruitment system and those undertaking background checking or vetting on our behalf.

If your application for employment with the Company is successful, your Personal Data may also be shared with certain interconnecting systems (such as HR information, payroll and benefits systems). More information will be provided to you in a separate notice during your on-boarding.

Certain third parties may be located outside of the EU/EEA, and in these cases we will use legally acceptable mechanisms, such as standard contractual clauses and from time to time other mechanisms provided for under applicable data protection laws, to ensure an adequate level of protection for your Personal Data. You are entitled to, upon request, a copy of documentation showing that appropriate safeguards have been taken to protect your Personal Data during such transfer.

**6\. Security of Personal Data**

We implement what we determine to be reasonable physical, technical and administrative security standards designed to protect your Personal Data from loss, misuse, alteration, destruction or damage.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our jobsites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee the security of your Personal Data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

**7\. Retention of your Personal Data**

Our general approach is to retain your application for a period of 6 months or, where you consent to a longer period of retention, for up to 2 years following the closure of the recruitment process for the role you applied for.

Otherwise, you should note that, in certain cases, legal or regulatory obligations require us to retain specific records for a set period of time.

If you accept employment with FactSet, your Personal Data will be held on the basis set out in our Employee Data Privacy Notice which will be shared with you.

**8\. Your rights**

The Company aims to ensure that all Personal Data are correct. You have the right to request correction of any inaccurate Personal Data relating to you, but you also have a responsibility to ensure that changes in personal circumstances are notified to the Company so that we can ensure that your Personal Data is up-to-date. In many cases, you will be able to "self-serve" corrections to your Personal Data through our jobsites or by contacting us by email.

_Access_. You have the right to request access to any of your Personal Data that the Company may hold.

_Withdrawal of consent_. You have the right to withdraw any consents at any time, for example if you are no longer happy for us to retain your unsuccessful application for an extended period of up to 2 years.

_Restriction_. You also have the right to restrict our processing of your Personal Data where:

  * you contest the accuracy of the Personal Data until we have taken sufficient steps to correct or verify its accuracy;
  * where the processing is unlawful but you do not want us to erase the Personal Data;
  * where we no longer need your Personal Data for the purposes of the processing, but you require such Personal Data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or
  * where you have objected to processing justified on legitimate interest grounds (see below) pending verification as to whether the Company has compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing.

Where your Personal Data is subject to restriction in this way we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

_Right to object_. Where we are relying upon legitimate interest to process your Personal Data (see section 4), then you have the right to object to that processing. Where we rely upon legitimate interest as a basis for processing we believe that we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds which permit us to continue the processing, but we will consider each case on an individual basis.

_Erasure_. You have the right to have your Personal Data erased under certain circumstances, such as when it is no longer needed by us for a lawful purpose.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you consider that the processing of your Personal Data infringes applicable law with the relevant local data protection authorities. In the UK, the supervisory authority is the Information Commissioner's Office ( **ICO** ).

For further information regarding your rights, to exercise any of your rights, or if you have any questions regarding the processing of your Personal Data please contact [recruiting@factset.com](mailto:recruiting@factset.com).

**9\. Changes to this Notice**

Any changes we may make to this Notice in the future will be posted on this page. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to this Privacy Notice.

EU/EEA Job Candidate Privacy Notice

## AAP/EEO Statement 

**_A NOTICE AND INVITATION TO ALL EMPLOYEES AND APPLICANTS_**

**_Philip Snow, Chief Executive Officer_**

_AFFIRMATIVE ACTION AND EQUAL EMPLOYMENT OPPORTUNITY POLICY STATEMENT_

FactSet Research Systems, Inc. has been and will continue to be an equal opportunity employer. To assure full implementation of this equal employment policy, we will take steps to assure that:

  1. Persons are recruited, hired, assigned and promoted without regard to race, national origin, religion, age, color, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, disability, or protected veteran status, or any other characteristic protected by local, state, or federal laws, rules, or regulations.
  2. All other personnel actions, such as compensa­tion, benefits, transfers, layoffs and recall from layoffs, access to training, education, tuition assistance and social recreation pro­grams are administered without regard to race, national origin, religion, age, color, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, disability, or protected veteran status, or any other characteristic protected by local, state, or federal laws, rules, or regulations.
  3. Employees and applicants shall not be subjected to harassment, intimidation, threats, coercion or discrimination because they have: (1) filed a complaint; (2) assisted or participated in an investigation, compliance review, hearing or any other activity related to the administration of any federal, state or local law requiring equal employment opportunity; (3) opposed any act or practice made unlawful by any federal, state or local law requiring equal opportunity or (4) exercised any other right protected by federal, state or local law requiring equal opportunity. 

I have appointed Kristen A. Panichella to take on the responsibili­ties of EEO Coordinator.  The EEO Coordinator will be respon­sible for the day to day imple­ment­a­tion and monitoring of the Company’s Affirmative Action Plan.  As part of that responsibil­ity, the EEO Coordinator will periodi­cally analyze the Company's personnel actions and their effects to ensure compliance with our equal employ­ment policy and administer the audit and reporting system. 

If you, as one of our employees or as an applicant for employment, have any questions about this policy or would like to view portions of the Affirmative Action Plan, please contact Leonard F. Johnson during regular business hours. This is also a reminder that employees may update their disability status at any time by contacting Kristen A. Panichella.

I have reviewed and fully endorse our Affirmative Action and Equal Employment Opportunity program.  In closing, I ask the continued assistance and support of all of the Company's personnel to attain our objec­tive of equal employment opportunity for all. 

Sincerely,

Philip Snow  
Chief Executive Officer

AAP/EEO Statement 

## External Referral Award Program Terms and Conditions

FactSet Research Systems Inc.’s External Referral Award Program (the “Program”) offers a one-time referral award to unaffiliated persons to help FactSet attract top talent at our offices located throughout the United States. To make a referral or learn more about the Program, please visit our External Referral Award Program webpage . Referrals are valid for 12 months from the date of submittal.

Please read the below carefully.  By submitting a resume via email, You (as defined below) agree to the following terms and conditions: 

**External Referrer (“You” or “Your”):**

  * Must be an individual person (i.e. not a business entity) who is at least 18 years of age and a legal resident of the United States in which you reside
  * Can’t be associated with or a consultant of a staffing or recruiting agency
  * Can’t be a current FactSet employee
  * Can’t refer yourself

**Your Referral Candidate:**

  * Can’t be a previous employee or current or former contractor for FactSet
  * Can’t be previously referred by a current FactSet employee
  * Can’t have already applied for the same position at FactSet on their own

If our team feels that Your referred candidate appears to be a match to our job requirements, we will reach out to them directly. The referred person must acknowledge that You referred them and we will ask the Referral Candidate to then apply directly on the Careers page of our website.

**Payment Terms**

If You are eligible to participate in the Program, FactSet shall pay You a one-time referral award in the form of an electronic gift card from one of FactSet’s preapproved retailers (“Award”) in the following (gross) amounts:

  * For Associate, Senior Associate, Specialist and Senior Specialist positions: $50 Award
  * For Senior Manager/AVP Lead, Manager, SVP or VP positions: $100 Award

FactSet will process the Award approximately 8-10 weeks after the referred employee is successfully hired and is actively employed by FactSet at the time the Award is to be paid. You are solely responsible for any appropriate state and federal taxes associated with the receipt of the Award.

In the event of a duplicate or competing submission of a referral candidate, payment will be made for the first referral candidate received by FactSet. Any Award payment is at FactSet’s sole discretion.

**Recruiters and Placement Agencies**

FactSet does not accept unsolicited resumes from recruiters or placement agencies. Please do not forward unsolicited resumes to our website or to any of our employees. FactSet will not pay any fees to any third-party agency or firm and will not be responsible for any fees associated with any unsolicited resume.  

**Additional Information**

  1. You may refer as many qualified referral candidates as You want, but the total aggregate Award amount You may receive is capped at $500.
  2. Referrals submitted in any other way other than outlined in these terms and conditions will not be eligible for the Program.
  3. These terms and conditions are governed by Connecticut law. You agree that in the event of any dispute between you and FactSet with respect to an Award the decision of FactSet will be final.
  4. The terms and conditions of the Program are subject to change or terminate at any time without notice and in FactSet’s sole discretion.
  5. Please email [referrals@factset.com](mailto:referrals@factset.com) with any questions.

External Referral Award Program Terms and Conditions
